Empresses in the Palace—the Legend of Zhen Huan
Adopted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
[translators] Carsen, and Lenny (debut)
[advisor/reviewer] Maxwell
[contact] carsenwei@yahoo.com
Email us to join our mailing list for subtitles update:)
Theme: Unfortunate Love
Perturbed by the thoughts on my mind
no matter how hard I try to sever my love.
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For all the lovers in the world,
who can break the spell of romance?
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For all the lovers in the world,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
[translators] Carsen, and Lenny (debut)
[advisor/reviewer] Maxwell
[contact] carsenwei@yahoo.com
Email us to join our mailing list for subtitles update:)
But you two are like sisters to each other.
Sisters share.
Your Highness wishes to remind
the women in the harem of good manners.
I do understand that jealousy and spite
are the flaws in a woman's character.
Dull-witted as I am,
I tolerate no flaws in my character.
But you can't expect other concubines to do the same.
Over all these years in the palace,
fickleness has been ever so constant in the human heart.
Thank Your Highness for the reminder.
Analects for Women always reminds us against strife and rivalries.
We will follow Your Highness's thoughtful advice.
It is very pleasant to converse with Lady Sourire.
And Lady Shen has a way with words just like your best friend.
This is nothing to be made light of.
So much for all the talks in the morning.
We will go.
Now you know how it is.
Meizhuang, do you think that I am in the wrong?
His Majesty would always
grow fond of concubines other than myself.
I'd rather it is you than anyone else.
Privately, I'm afraid the other concubines would do harm to myself.
But you won't.
Meizhuang.
You are the only one I can trust in the palace.
We are friends with Lingrong
but that's not like us growing up together.
We have to support each other through the decades yet to come.
Meizhuang, there are things that I cannot foresee or forbid.
No matter what the future holds,
our friendship will never change.
I hope you won't keep me at a distance
if His Majesty keeps his fondness of me.
His fondness is always expected for who you are.
Otherwise, we have to survive in the harem to protect our families.
(thunder rumbling)
Why are you awake?
I heard the rain.
Do you have something on your mind?
No.
Don't lie to me.
Your Majesty, I'm scared.
Of what?
Did Your Majesty know that
the most beloved concubine is also the most resented?
Did anyone give you trouble?
No, no one did.
The rain tends to every flower in the harem
so they can bloom and bear fruits.
I dare not wish for Your Majesty's exclusive love.
Why not?
The concubines are inextricably intertwined
with the powers at the imperial court.
Your Majesty is a sensible emperor.
Am I?
It's been seven days.
It will be more difficult for Your Majesty to administer
the state affairs if the harem is plagued by strife.
And the neglect of concubines will bring complaints
about the fickleness in Your Majesty's affection.
I cannot tolerate anything to Your Majesty's annoyance.
All right.
Peace and grace to Mother.
Have a seat.
Thank you, Mother.
You seem to be in good spirits today.
Are you satisfied with the concubines lately?
Yes, especially Lady Sourire.
Lady Sourire?
I don't recall you talking about her.
She's the smart one that was selected last year.
She's been sick until recently.
That's good.
It's important that you have someone you like.
Unlike Prince XVII,
who still hasn't settled down with a wife.
He hasn't been visiting for some days.
I wonder how he has been.
Mother, if you miss him, I'll summon him after lunch.
He is a filial son.
But he always reminds me of his birth mother,
Consort Serein, who your father favored exclusively.
She became the target for harem-wide resentment.
(chuckle) An old woman gabs
when she has all the time in the world to overthink.
I benefit from your golden advice, Mother.
When you have a moment,
I'll send Lady Sourire here to seek your advice.
There are more women than flowers in the harem.
Noble Ladies are like the ubiquitous little wild flowers.
I'll see her when she makes it to Concubine.
Certainly.
Madam Sun, did Consort Fleur come lately?
Her Highness has been busy with housekeeping.
The Empress came this morning to serve medicine.
But Concubine Beauté was here yesterday for quite a long talk.
Concubine Beauté.
(noticing the name tag for Concubine Beauté)
The writing on Concubine Beauté's name tag is illegible.
Make a new one and send it in after a few days.
(touching the name tag for Lady Sourire)
Peace to Your Highness.
Xiao-Xiazi, what brought you here?
Your Highness, His Majesty is on the way to your palace.
So I came here to notify Your Highness.
His Majesty is coming?
(gasp) Is he really?
(gasp)
Quickly, put this away.
And that one.
- Ouch!
- Your Highness.
Your Highness, please be careful.
(laughing inwardly) How am I going to
meet him in all this hurry-scurry?
Your Highness knows His Majesty
inside and out after all these years.
His Majesty hasn't visited for almost a year.
I can't believe this is happening.
Is Your Highness not happy?
I am. I am.
Go quickly get the dress for me.
The pink one. His Majesty likes me in pink.
- Go quickly.
- Yes, Your Highness.
- Stop standing there. Do my hair!
Wait, go send for the Third Prince.
Your Highness, His Majesty comes here to see you.
The Third Prince will disturb your quality time with him.
That's true. That kid is not a good talker.
- Never mind, do my hair.
- Yes.
Allow me to take my leave.
Your Highness, please take a break and have some cubilose.
Did His Majesty select her again?
His Majesty selected Consort Astuce.
How's that possible?
Anyone is better than Lady Sourire.
What time is it now?
The night just began to fall.
His Majesty was hoping that Lady Shen could help with bookkeeping.
I will teach her.
Go bring her here.
The candles are too bright.
Put out two for me.
His Majesty selected Consort Astuce tonight.
That's just as well.
It sounds like you are happy but upset, My Lady.
I'm so confused.
I was hoping His Majesty would not come,
but I feel bad when he doesn't.
Lady Shen's handwriting isn't expected to be
of an educated woman from a respectable family.
The candlelight was dim.
I hope Your Highness can forgive me.
You understand the levels of spending from the daybook.
I have to set an example of frugality as the head of the concubines.
I believe that one can write beautifully even with her eyes closed.
The lighting is not a sufficient excuse.
I ... will make another copy.
All right, I will have a doze.
Song Zhi, the light is too bright.
Blow out two more candles.
Yes.
Have a seat.
I'm all right to stand by Your Majesty.
You're blocking the light when I'm reading.
(gasp) I'm sorry.
Your Majesty, chrysanthemum tea helps
relieve eye strain from reading at night.
You just brought me ginseng tea.
I forgot.
Your Majesty, the Third Prince grew taller.
In his adulthood?
Oh, I mean, he grew stronger.
He goes to the hunting ground every day.
He follows Your Majesty's guidance strictly.
I hope he does.
He does, he studies late every night,
and rises before dawn for horseback archery.
I say to him every time I see him:
"Hongshi, you must listen to your Father;
You must live up to his expectations as his eldest son;
I hope you can carry his burden in the future."
You've talked his ear off with those words,
and mine too.
Do you have something new to say to your son?
Yes, I ...
The dress doesn't look good on you.
Don't wear it again.
Your Majesty, I remember you saying you like me in pink.
It's not for your age.
Does Your Majesty think I'm old?
I'm just being honest.
Lake blue and emerald green are much more appropriate.
Don't stay up late.
Where is Your Majesty going?
To the Hall of Mental Cultivation.
Your Majesty ... Your Majesty ...
I imagine Consort Astuce is very much pleased to see His Majesty.
Don't overthink, My Lady.
"Rain pouring over Lake Dongting;
mist clouding over Temple Huangling."
"For my love I’m here waiting,
and the haze over the ruffled water to clear."
My Lady, don't play this song.
It's bad luck to play The Lament of the Xiang River Concubines.
The Xiang River concubines are not
as lamentable as these in the palace.
Why should I even lament?
I asked him to go.
Stop.
Are we going back or to the Palace of Earthly Honor?
To the Palace of Pearl Jade.
Stop.
Put down the sedan chair.
The Lament of the Xiang River Concubines
I'm musically illiterate.
“I see the gloomy clouds in the music,
in her keen eyes on the ruffled water.”
[quoted from Listening to The Lament of the Xiang River Concubines]
She's sad when I'm not with her.
The music disquiets my heart.
Peace and grace to Your Majesty.
Rise.
What brings Your Majesty here?
"Pale and haggard grows the yearner for his lover."
I learned what that means today.
Did Your Majesty not visit Consort Astuce?
I did.
I was wondering what you were doing
when I saw the moon on my way back.
It's fortunate that I didn't miss the wonderful music.
I feel abashed by your flattery.
How come an emperor takes to eavesdropping?
How dare you!
You'll play another song as compensation.
Consort Astuce would feel bad about your leave.
Would you not feel sad if I stayed with her?
Your Majesty agreed to be a sensible emperor.
I will tomorrow.
I will be a bad emperor for tonight.
I will be a good concubine tomorrow
and entreat Consort Astuce's pardon.
Si Lang, what would you like to listen to?
[si=the 4th (son); lang=an endearment for one's husband]
What did you just call me?
I'm sorry.
No, I like it.
Your name is Zhen Huan, and do you have a sobriquet?
I don't.
Can I call you Huan Huan?
Huan Huan.
(yawning)
You have finished?
I made two copies in compensation for my poor handwriting,
if Your Highness would like to have a look.
It's getting late. You shall leave.
I will let you know after I read through it.
Yes, I bid Your Highness goodbye.
Consort Fleur was purposely making it difficult for you.
The account book was full of numbers,
and she dimmed the lights down.
Your eyes are red after writing the two copies.
What can I do? She's Consort Fleur.
Why don't you tell His Majesty, My Lady?
She is teaching me at the behest of His Majesty.
Would His Majesty still allow me
to learn about palace management if I tell him?
I don't make the gain to lose more.
I was simply worried about you, My Lady.
All right, I don't feel tired any more.
The Thousand Carp Pond is in the vicinity.
Let's go for a walk.
His Majesty had the pond lit up
so we can see the red fishes at night.
We are running out of fish food.
Xiao-Shi, go get more.
Look at that, My Lady.
I've finally seen you here, My Lady.
I've been looking around.
What brings you here, Madam?
Is there anything I can I do for Her Highness?
Her Highness was going to reward you
with the ink she received from Guizhou Province.
But you were lost to sight.
Well, I'll let Lunar go with you, Madam.
- But you'll be here alone, My Lady.
- You'll be back shortly.
Help! H... Help!
Help!
His Majesty the Emperor.
I bow in respect before Your Majesty.
- Rise.
- I thank Your Majesty.
How is she?
My Lady, Lady Shen is out of danger.
But she is unconscious due to water inhalation.
We have written prescriptions for her
to recover quickly from the after effects.
But ...
Don't mince your words.
Yes, I was going to say that it will take
some time for Lady Shen to make a full recovery.
You must spare no effort as her personal doctor.
We will go prepare the medicine.
We don’t have time to be punctilious.
Meizhuang.
How did this happen?
I beg Your Majesty's pardon.
Explain in detail how Lady Shen fell into the pond.
I do not know.
That's insane!
How can you not know as the servants by her side?
I beg for Your Highness's pardon.
I was going to get more fish food
while My Lady was feeding the carp.
The news came to me when I was on my way.
Lunar, what about you?
Song Zhi told us that Consort Fleur
wished to reward My Lady with ink sticks.
I went with her when she found us by the pond.
In that case, not a servant was with Lady Shen at that time?
Your Majesty, Consort Fleur is here.
What brings you here so late at night?
I heard that Lady Shen nearly drowned.
How is she?
Look for yourself.
Poor thing, how could this happen to a girl as pretty as a flower?
Your Highness, please don't worry. The doctors said
she will be fine when she regains consciousness.
Your Majesty, the guards were inefficiently
on patrol to come to Lady Shen's timely rescue.
This is my negligence in managing the palace.
I shall receive a punishment.
The guards patrol on scheduled shifts.
If you are to be punished,
the Empress should be held responsible as well.
Stupid servants!
How could you let this happen to Lady Shen,
and disturb His Majesty?
Useless.
These servants are a burden on Lady Shen.
I suggest they be sent to the Department of Penalty.
Your Majesty, Xiao-Shi and Lunar didn't act appropriately.
But they do not deserve to be sent to the Department of Penalty.
This is necessary for maintaining discipline in the palace.
The imperial ponds will be our swimming pools
if there are more servants like them.
You are also responsible for the
incompetent servants in your palace.
I will follow Your Highness's advice.
I will strictly discipline the servants.
(sobbingly) I am guilty of not taking good care of My Lady.
I beg Your Highness to allow me to serve until My Lady awakes
before I report myself to the Department of Penalty.
Shameless flunky!
Are you expecting Lady Shen to
intercede for you when she awakes?
I wish Your Highness would pardon her.
Lunar and Xiao-Shi are partially responsible for the accident.
Instead of being punished, they may as well
make compensation by looking after Meizhuang.
So Lady Sourire does not think they deserve punishment?
Leniency towards these two servants
will send out the message to many
that servants can be exempt from punishment
if they compensate for their mistakes.
It is necessary to separate punishment and compensation.
But Lunar and Xiao-Shi have served Meizhuang all along.
It is undesirable for Meizhuang
to have her trusted servants away.
Why should they stay with Lady Shen
when they could not even take care of her?
The Thousand Carp Pond is less than 100 feet from my palace.
How can I tolerate their mistake?
That is exactly why I am concerned.
People might misunderstand Your Highness,
thinking that Your Highness is so irate
because the incident happened near your palace
rather than Your Highness cares about Lady Shen.
Punishing the servants might harm Your Highness's prestige.
I hope Your Highness will reconsider.
I agree with Lady Sourire.
We should wait until Lady Shen awakes
and decide on the punishments for her servants.
I wonder if it's appropriate for me to make another suggestion.
Go ahead.
We don't know yet how Meizhuang fell into the pond.
But the guards must be
held responsible for their delayed rescue.
I would suggest replacing the guards
at the Palace of Earthly Honor
in case Her Highness might suffer such an accident.
Lady Sourire pardons the servants but punishes my guards.
Isn't that unfair?
I'm thinking for Your Highness.
Your Highness takes priority in the palace.
Your palace must be protected by better guards.
And it isn't a punishment to replace the guards.
Nothing else matters as much as your safety.
This must not happen again.
Su Peisheng will select elite guards for your palace
so that I can be relieved.
I thank Your Majesty.
I brought Lady Shen the best wild ginseng
for her to recover from the after effects.
Not a moment have you stopped looking after the harem.
You should go have some rest.
Your Majesty as well,
you need to go to court early in the morning.
I had my servants cooking ejiao longan soup when I left.
It must be ready by now.
Would Your Majesty like to have some before you sleep?
That's very thoughtful of you.
I'm feeling hungry.
Would you like to go with us?
The Palace of Earthly Honor makes the best food in the palace.
I am terribly flattered, Your Majesty.
Lady Sourire, please come with us.
I would very much like to,
but I wish to stay here for Meizhuang.
I hope Your Majesty will have one more serving for me.
All right, don't get too tired.
I bid Your Majesty goodbye.
I bid Your Highness goodbye.
His Majesty is leaving.
It's very late now.
Your Highness should get some rest.
Certainly, but you as well.
Is Your Highness not feeling like to sleep?
Would you like something to eat?
I feel terrible for Lady Shen.
What is Your Highness's take on it?
(huff)
Ejiao longan soup.
She was all well-prepared.
Both Your Highness and Lady Sourire could see that
Consort Fleur showed up neat and tidy
as if it was all part of a plan.
A fox must hide her tail well
when pretending to be a dog.
But she was too pleased with herself to cover her tail.
She wouldn't bother to.
She must assure an yes to her inviting soup.
Of course she couldn't dress any less nicely.
But His Majesty might have been
too worried about Lady Shen to notice that.
Should we point this out to His Majesty?
(snort)
What good would that do?
Now that Consort Fleur has her eye on our palace,
trying to find fault in everything we do,
we shouldn't point out one to her.
It's 2 am now, My Lady.
You should get some rest.
I can't.
I'm anxious.
Me too, My Lady.
I just can't fathom how My Lady
could have lost her footing.
Do you remember seeing anything strange at that time?
I have a suspicion, however.
How come this happened
as soon as both of you left?
Now that Meizhuang is in a state of unconsciousness,
we'll all be kept in the dark
if you forgot to mention anything.
My Lady, I know this is serious,
but I wasn't sure about what I saw and dared not say anything.
You must report every detail for such a serious matter.
On my way back to the pond,
I might have seen a eunuch dash past the pond.
But I couldn't see with clarity in the dark.
Did you mention it to anyone else?
I dare not bring it up to anyone.
Remember,
don't speak of this to anyone.
Do you understand?
I won't.
That bitch even made His Majesty replace my guards.
It caused me so much inconvenience.
Don't be upset, Your Highness.
It's not worth it.
How dare she tread on my face?
Don't worry, Your Highness.
Now that she's the most favored concubine of His Majesty,
her haters are all over the place.
Who's serving Yu at the moment?
I heard that she has been such a grump
that she even kicked out her maids.
Now she's all by herself.
How about the apprentice of your useless eunuch, Kang Luhai?
Is he loyal to you?
Did Your Highness mean Xiao-Yinzi?
He is all right,
not as sly as his shifu.
Let's send him to work for Yu.
This is a gift from the Governor of Shandong Province.
I know nothing about ink appreciation.
I hope Your Majesty would enlighten me.
This is the Mandarin Duck Ink.
It is hard as jade and smooth as glue.
It is also decorated on both sides
with mandarin ducks in gold color.
Mandarin ducks are a lifelong loving couple.
They represent you and His Majesty.
He never fails to please me.
But the inkstick would be more useful
at the Palace of Earthly Honor.
The inkstick there was used to set up a deadly trap.
It was useful but evil.
Don't speak your mind out loud.
Is Your Majesty not going to do anything about that?
If you remember how Consort Fleur
swaggered into my palace this morning,
you could tell the conclusion His Majesty made.
(snort)
What can I do even if I want to?
But we all know who is behind this.
It doesn't matter that we know
as long as His Majesty is not in the know.
His Majesty always wishes for a peaceful harem.
Some cases are settled by being unsettled.
Send Lady Shen some health tonics.
Meizhuang, you're awake.
Are you feeling hungry?
Would you like something to eat?
(sobbingly) Huan'er!
There was ... someone trying to kill me!
Meizhuang, did you see who it was?
He ... he pushed my from behind ...
I couldn't see his face.
He did it forcibly ...
It must be a eunuch or a guard!
There are countless eunuchs and guards in the palace.
Did you see who it was?
Enemies are friendly in the palace,
but they wouldn't be so vicious as to take my life.
The one who could possibly do this to me ... must be ...
(coughing)
But the Thousand Carp Pond is just
a stone's throw away from her palace.
Does she not even have the decency to be discreet?
Discreet?
That was the last thing she wanted to be.
Last night, she came here all dolled up and domineering,
and almost sent Lunar and Xiao-Shi to jail.
She left triumphantly with His Majesty to her palace.
You went into the pond
within a hundred steps from her palace.
Whoever in the palace dared
commit this in her territory?
No one, other than herself.
"The triumphant troops make dangerous moves."
No one would suspect that
she would do it at such an indiscreet location.
Now that His Majesty is very fond of you,
we are fledging to escape her control over the harem.
So she tries to shoot one down
and let the other fly with only one wing.
Meizhuang, I'm so sorry.
I took you into this nightmare.
It has nothing to do with you.
She has always seen me as fish bone in her throat.
She didn't do it earlier due to His Majesty's
attention to me and my utmost forbearance.
Meizhuang, what do you plan to do now?
What can I do?
I have no evidence against
His Majesty's favorite concubine.
I will tell His Majesty
that I ...
that I lost my footing.
That might be all we can do for now.
I'm unable to do anything this time,
but I won't let her have her way all my life.
As long as I'm breathing,
I'm counting every second!
Theme: The Lonely Phoenix
[phoenix is the symbol of an empress]
[translators] Carsen, and Lenny (debut)
[advisor/reviewer] Maxwell
[contact] carsenwei@yahoo.com
Email us to join our mailing list for subtitles update:)
I dimly recall the colorful blooms in every summer.
They are as distant as the autumn moon in the water.
He loved me with a volatile heart.
And before I knew it, we fell apart.
Behind me are the promises and longing.
Before me lie the flute and the zither.
I loved you with my body and soul
But you hurt me from head to toe.
My wish ran athwart
and I ended up a fool of my destiny.
My love was the wind-swept flowers from a tree.
A plum bloomed in winter hoping for a fruitful summer.
But the irresistible winds of destiny destroyed her wish.
You can hear the flapping of a phoenix
but you will never see it.
What you see is the falling leaves from the phoenix tree.
The falling leaves from the phoenix tree.